Hello everyone, how are you all? I am your
personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma and you are
watching Yudh Real. The title of today's video is of
Mr. Sandeep Sharma.
He has commented this comment in the comment section of the video of Assured Savings Plan of Aditya Birla Sun
Life Insurance Company Limited.
If you also
want to come and understand the details of the savings plan, then check the life insurance playlist on the channel
and
you will find the link of the playlist in the description of the video.
Mr. Sharma ji,
thank you very much for your comment.
Before starting the video, you are requested to
like the video because this shows
us that you want us to keep
bringing videos as per your suggestions and questions. Watch the video till the end. If you
like it, share it. If you have subscribed to the channel, then
definitely turn on the notifications by clicking on the all notification bell. So let's
start today's video and
know the details of Fortune Ali Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited.
This plan is a unit linked
and non-participating life
insurance plan. In simple words,
you will get life cover in it based on the premium you pay annually, that is
If death occurs during the policy term,
your nominee will receive a fixed amount, irrespective of the
market conditions.
Your premium will be paid through the fund chosen by you. In
such a situation, you will get returns based on the performance of the fund, that is, the
risk will be yours. Talking about the
entry limit, a
plan can be taken even for a 30-day-old child and
for a person of maximum 65 years, the
policy term option is available from 10 years
to 40 years.
You get multiple options for premium payment term,
such as 5 years, 10 years, along with
15 years and 20 years. Along with this,
if you are taking this plan
and someone's age or your
age is more than 55 years, then the minimum
premium payment term option will be
10 years. The minimum annual premium
limit is Rs 40,000. Now when it comes to
life cover, the minimum
life cover amount will be  It will be ₹4 lakh.
In other words,
your minimum SAM Asort, which we call
life cover, will be 10 times your annual basic premium. When it comes to top-up premium, the
minimum limit for top-up premium
is ₹5000 and
you also
get life cover on the top-up premium that you pay, which is one and a quarter times your top-up
premium, which we
call 125%. If we talk about the mode of premium, you get
annual, half-yearly, monthly and monthly modes. If
you choose the monthly mode, then auto-
debit will happen from your account. Now we
will know the
details of investment option i.e. portfolio investment option. The
first is Systematic Transfer Option. If you
choose this option, then your
basic money, after de-charges, will be
transferred to the liquid fund. It will be
invested. After that, it will
automatically keep getting transferred to the funds that you have chosen.
On monthly mode, the choice of
funds that are available are Income Advantage and Nature
Creator Maximizer Multiply. Out of
all these funds, you can choose the maximum amount.  You can choose only four funds
under the Systematic Transfer
Option. The second option you get is the
Return Optimizer Option. This option includes two
funds. The first is an equity
fund called Maximize. The second is the Income
Advantage Fund, which is a depth fund. As soon as
you have 10% in equity, its value will be
10% of your base investment. This value will be
transferred to the Income Advantage Fund. This way, the value will be
liquid and the risk on it will be reduced
because it is going to the depth fund.
If the value is not 10%
or less than your base premium,
then nothing will be transferred. The
amount in the Income Advantage Fund will remain
in the Maximize Fund, i.e., the equity fund.
All this will continue to happen automatically;
you do not have to do anything. The third
option is Self-Managed. Now, here
you get the options of depth and equity funds.
You can choose the funds yourself:
Liquid Plus, Income Advantage, Protector
Builder, Natural Creator Fund, and Equity.  The
fund options that you get are coming
on your screen right now, first
among them is Asset Allocation Fund, second is
Magnifer Fund, then your Maximizer Fund,
Feeder Super 20
Equity Fund, Value and Momentum Fund, Munch
Fund, Kept Nifty Index Fund and
Multiply Fund. Here you choose the fund yourself
and manage it yourself, the name
of this option is Self Manage. Turn the video on full
screen. If you have
chosen the systematic transfer option and
want to switch to its self-management, then you will be
able to do so in a different fund also, but
if you have taken the return optimizer option, then
you will not be able to switch in it or
you will not be able to switch from it, okay,
you can read it here. Now let us talk about the
benefits, see, the first benefit
in it is the Guaranteed Addition, which
starts getting given from the tenth year of the policy and
you keep getting it every 5 years, right, so the
amount of Guaranteed Addition will be 2
percent of your total paid premium,
which you would have paid in the last 60 months,
along with this, the policy will be
yours from the fourth year.  Average fund value
means 0.35% addition to the average fund value of one year.
You will also get a guaranteed addition.
Now the second benefit in this
is debt benefit. It is obvious that
we take ULIP only to get life
cover. So what happens is that in ULIP plan,
fund value is compared.
Parcel withdrawal is deducted from the base sum amount.
If any has been done in the last two years, then the
higher amount among the two is paid to your nominee as
debt benefit. If
top up premium has been paid here, then the
fund value of the top up premium you paid or the top up summation
you got on the basis of the
top up premium paid, both will be
compared. The
amount which is higher among the two is paid to your nominee here.
Now the third option,
that is the third benefit, is obvious,
you get it in this.
What do you get as cylinder value? You get only the fund value.  When do you
get the fund value? Directly when you
surrender the policy after the completion of the first five years. But if you surrender or stop paying the premium
five years before the completion of the first five years of the policy, then the
fund of the policy is
transferred to the policy discontinuance fund
and in such a case the return is
fixed at a minimum rate of 4 percent. In
such a case the fund management
charges are also reduced which are
levied on your fund value at the rate of 0.50% annually. And you know that the
maturity benefit in a ULIP plan is
your fund value. There is
no need to tell this because this is what happens. The
next benefit is the
parcel withdrawal limit here that
you will not be able to parcel for the first 5 years.
If you are less than 18 years then also you will not be able to do it.
How much can you do?
You can withdraw 25% of your fund value. The
minimum parcel withdrawal limit is within a year.  The
top premium of Rs 5000 that you
pay also has a locking period of 5 years.
Therefore, if
you take this plan, it may be
better to take it for the long term. Now when it comes to
switching, you can switch
from one fund to another and from one portfolio
strategy to another portfolio strategy
option, but the
minimum switch amount should be Rs 5000.
You
also get the option of premium ledger in the plan.
Premium ledger means that
you can decide that this much amount should go to a particular
fund or this much should not go to a particular fund.
Now we will know the details of the charges.
So first of all, the charges here are policy
discontinuation charges. If your annual
premium is up to Rs 50000 and
you discontinue the policy in the first year, then
20% of your annual basic premium or
20% of the average fund value or
Rs 3000, out of these three.  The lower amount will be charged,
i.e., you can charge up to a maximum of ₹3,000.
If the premium is more than ₹50,000, then
6% of the annual premium,
6% of your average fund value for the year, which is
also being called the base fund value here, or
₹6,000, whichever is less.
In other words, if you
surrender or discontinue the policy in the second year, a
maximum
discontinuation charge of ₹2,000 will be levied. If the premium
is less than ₹50,000 or up to ₹50,000, then a charger of up to
₹5,000 will be levied. If the premium is more than ₹50,000, then a
charge of up to ₹5,000 can be levied. If the
policy is discontinued in the third year of the policy, then a
maximum charge of up to ₹150,000 can be levied.
If the premium is up to ₹50,000 or
more than that, then a charge of up to ₹4,000 can be levied.
If the policy is continued in the fourth year of the policy
and the
premium is  If the premium is up to ₹50000 then a maximum
charge of ₹1000 can be levied and if the premium is
more than ₹50000 then a charge of up to ₹2000 can be levied.
We can do this by paying attention here
because it has been said that whichever is less among these, the
three options that have been told to you will
also be charged. You will be charged premium allocation charges
if the premium is from ₹40000 to
less than ₹2.5 lakh then
you will be charged 50% of your base premium.
If the premium is more than ₹2.5 lakh
then you will be charged 0.500 percent
premium allocation charges on the first year
of the policy and also on the second year. In the
third year of the policy, you will be charged premium allocation
charges if the premium is from ₹40000 to less than ₹2.5 lakh
then 5% of your
base premium will be charged. If the premium is ₹250000
then you will be charged
premium allocation charges at the rate of 4 percent. Now Dilex  No matter
how much more than this, four percent
is fixed here. Premium location charges will be levied on the top-up premium.
Two percent of the top-up premium is fixed here. Now we are talking about
fund management charges here, so turn the video on
full screen. If you have
invested in any of the Liquid Plus Fund, Income Advantage Fund, Usher Fund, Protector Friend or Builder Fund, then
annual fund management
charges will be levied at the rate of one percent on the value of your fund. Annual fund management charges will be levied at the rate of one and a quarter percent on the
fund value. For nh4 Creator Captain Nifty
Index Fund and Asset Allocation Fund,
if you have invested in Munch Magnifier Multiplier Super 20
Pure Equity & Value & Momentum Fund, then
fund management charges may be levied at the rate of 1.5%. Policy
administration charges are 0.6%
of your annual premium, which can go up to a maximum of ₹6000.
Imagine, you are charged charges
at Rs.50. Switch okay. Now with this, we
talk about parcel withdrawal
charges here, you will have to pay Rs.50 for that too.  There are
miscellaneous charges on every transaction. Now when it comes to miscellaneous
charges, you will be charged ₹50 per transaction.
If your policy bond gets lost and you
need a duplicate copy, then you will be charged up to ₹250.
Now, like the 50-50
charges that I told you, like switch charge,
parcel withdrawal charge, miscellaneous charge, these
charges can increase in the future and can go up to ₹500. Let us take an
example. Let us take a
Mr. A. He has taken a policy for long term
ULIP. His age is 30 years
because he believes that if he
invests for long term, he can get profit. So,
in such a situation, he has taken a policy for 30 years
and the premium payment that he is making for 10 years is
₹1 lakh annually. In
such a situation, the live cover i.e. the
sum assured amount becomes ₹1000000
here because the annual
premium is reduced by 10 times here. There is a
condition in the plan that in any situation,
which  The minimum death benefit will not be
less than 105% of the premium paid by you. Let's watch the
video on full
screen. We have taken this screenshot from the browser
and here we are going to
invest in the maximum fund because equity is the best
fund, so the returns can be higher. At the rate of 4%, the return is
shown up to 18.25 lakh i.e. 1825000 and at the rate of 8%, the return is up to 18.25 lakh i.e. 21524.
Rest, if death occurs, you know the
fund value and whichever amount is higher among the two will be
paid to the nominee.
Now why did I
not do a separate calculation? See, this is a ULIP plan,
even after doing the calculation, it will not be done exactly. If it does not happen exactly, then there is
no use in showing you the calculation here
because it is clearly written in the policy brochure that
everything
depends on the market. On the basis of returns, the grace
period is 30 days for annual, slow
mode of premium and for monthly mode of
premium.  The free period is 15 days. If you
buy directly, it is 15 days. If you
buy indirectly, it is 30 days.
Thank you very much for watching the video till the end. Understand one thing yourself and
explain it to others also that insurance is a
protection. Protection is never taken incomplete.
You will get the complete PDF of information
on the Telegram channel and I
always tell you that if you are investing in a ULIP plan or
any other plan, then
definitely read the policy document and
definitely get that PDF from Telegram.
Thank you very much.